Isasumi, Chilchuk?
Do you mind slowing down a bit?
The floor is full of gaps and it's hard to walk on.
I didn't even notice.
Let's take a little break.
Sure, whatever you say, Grandpa.
There's something I've been wondering.
In these bodies,
what's the gap between our actual age and the age we look?
Laios, how old are you?
I'm 26 years old.
Senshi, now that he's a dwarf,
how old does Laios look to you?
Hmm, I would say around 60.
Dwarves live about two and a half times longer than tall men.
So if I'm 26 as a tall man,
I'd be 65 as a dwarf.
If our appearance adjusts our age relative to what race we are,
I'm kind of worried about our remaining lifespan.
Will we age at the rate we did before we transformed?
Or will that change based on our new bodies?
Hey, Marcel,
if you think that doesn't affect you, you're wrong.
Since you're a half foot now,
if it's the latter,
you'll only live till about 50 years old.
In less than 40 years,
you're gonna get all old and wrinkly and then die.
A half foot's lifespan is that short?
I thought they lived to 100.
There are some who live that long.
But it's pretty rare.
I'm only kidding.
What I'm actually trying to say is,
if that was the case,
then this mushroom is too good to be true.
There are tons of people out there
who would pay a fortune to become another race,
but I've never seen this mushroom in the markets.
It means the change is only temporary
or has some kind of awful side effect.
Side effects, huh?
Possibly.
I thought about using the changelings for something,
but I don't think it'd go well.
What kind of something?
You want to be a demi-human, don't you?
No, that's not it.
I was honestly thinking more in regards to Fallon.
What about her?
Now, this is all hypothetical,
but what if everything worked out
and we defeated the Mad Mage?
I've learned my lesson.
Fallon regains her sanity.
Huh?
What was I just doing?
Fallon's back!
We return to the surface.
Man, that was really rough, wasn't it?
She scares people.
So, in that case,
having a dragon's lower half would be a problem.
Hold on.
Let's hear what he has to say.
I thought about hiding that part by putting her in a hole.
What can I get to?
However,
a large monster can't survive in a human town
with how thin the mana is.
Like how a fish can't survive outside of water,
Fallon might not be able to live among humans anymore.
Unless...
We use those mushrooms.
With the changelings,
we could change her lower half
into another type of dragon
that's smaller.
And that way,
Fallon could live in town after all!
What?
He's so stupidly optimistic.
Miss!
Though,
I won't deny wanting to change into something else, too.
Tall men don't have any kind of special trait,
which makes us plain.
Jilchuk,
do you hear something strange?
Oh, uh,
do you think it's the dwarven relic or something?
No,
it's like stones scraping against each other.
From what I can tell,
it actually sounds like it's getting closer.
This is bad!
The gargoyles found us!
You idiot!
Did you really not shut the door all the way?
We need to hurry and get out of here
before they catch up to us!
They're just gonna keep chasing us
unless we do something.
Let's set up an ambush and take them down.
But, Laios...
I'll draw them to me.
Jilchuk,
get the pan!
Izutsumi,
attack from behind!
Senji,
wait for an opening.
Marcel,
where are they?
I told you!
They're right there!
Laios!
Dammit!
Watch out, everyone!
Now do you understand
why I quickly run off
and find a place to hide?
Don't stand around people's legs!
You say that, but...
You're clumsy no matter what body you're in, huh?
This way!
Where did this smoke come from?
Did you cast something?
Are you two hurt?
No, we're fine.
It went right between our arms.
Good.
You mind grabbing Kensuke for me?
Sure.
Has it always looked like this?
No.
How and when did it change, then?
You think that maybe the smoke we saw
was actually changeling spores?
But, hang on.
There wasn't a mushroom ring anywhere near here.
Our arms were a ring when it passed through them.
Wait, so that means...
Quit buzzing around, dammit!
You guys!
Grab each other's hands
and make a circle right now!
Think before you open your mouth for once!
Just trust me, okay?
Well?
What do we do now?
Is this it?
We're gonna have the gargoyle
pass through our arms.
If my theory is correct,
then the gargoyle
should change into something else!
All right, it's time!
The wall's in that direction!
Come this way!
Hey!
Stop!
You're hurting me!
Oh, no!
It can't fly away anymore!
Come on!
Let's surround it!
We did it!
Where'd it go?
Look!
This is the gargoyle?
It really did change.
I see.
It works like this, too.
So non-living,
things transform faster!
Glyos!
Are you okay?
My head hurts,
but I'm fine.
Dwarves' bodies
are as tough as they say.
Doesn't seem like
it's gonna come down here.
How are we supposed
to get it to pass
through our arms?
Marcil?
Yeah?
What if we...
It should work.
What should...
Let's do it!
Right.
We're gonna bring
ourselves closer to it
and get it to attack us!
Keep in rhythm
so we run and sink!
Let's go!
One!
Two!
One and two and one
and two and one
and two and...
It's making its move!
You ready to do this?
Ready!
Ready for what?
Ready and...
Take to the sky, Marcil!
Marcil!
Ah!
Good riddance.
It's kind of anticlimactic,
but if you wash off
the spores stuck to your body,
you'll go back to normal.
Can you please not?
All it is is water,
so it's fine.
Gotta rinse the spores
off thoroughly.
We're basically
the mushroom seedbed
right now.
I think I finally understand
why the mushrooms
behave the way they do.
An animal steps
into a changeling ring
and transforms.
They get shunned
by their kind,
then they die,
and eventually
become new changelings.
What an awful
side effect.
Since we're not gargoyles,
it's gonna take some time
to go back to how we were.
Why don't we prepare
a meal while we wait?
Very well.
Kensuke,
it's hard to believe
that this is you now.
Maybe it's a bit of a stretch
to think the mushrooms
were the cause of this.
Will washing you
change you back?
What's on the menu?
We have some leftover dumplings,
so I'll be boiling those.
Really?
Again?
Is there a problem with that?
Nah,
I'm just kind of sick of them.
Sick of them?
Wish I could be that carefree.
Let's cook them another way.
Heat some oil in a frying pan,
then gently put the dumplings in.
Oh, shit.
When golden brown,
remove the dumplings
and blot the excess oil.
On top of Izutsumi
having a small appetite,
she won't eat anything
she doesn't like.
So it's important
I take extra care
to make sure
she eats her fill.
Tell me,
what do you think?
You just fried them.
Could you not?
Huh?
What if...
Oh, it changed its shape.
It seems as though
the mouth does indeed
act as a changeling ring.
And there are many different
kinds of dumplings
in the world.
What if eating that
makes mushrooms start sprouting
inside our stomachs?
That didn't happen
when we ate
the hippogriff meat
thanks to digestion.
Isn't it great?
Now then, Izutsumi,
help me set the dishware.
It's ready.
So much variety.
There's barrel-mess meat
in this one.
Oh, lamb meat, huh?
The insides change too.
No way, I got cheese.
This one tastes sweet.
I can't figure out
the meat in mine.
Hey, keep your stupid legs
out of my face!
Meat!
My body is finally
back to normal!
Damn it.
What a lousy way
to wake up.
Thank goodness.
I've never been happier.
All right.
I think we should
start heading out.
Actually, let's change
into lighter clothing first.
It's pretty warm
on this floor.
You know, this is the
perfect temperature
for creatures to breed in.
Though the more
we keep going,
who knows if we're gonna
see all that much
life up ahead.
I should have made
some sausage to prepare
for this kind of thing.
Hang on.
Didn't you make some
before, using the
red dragon meat?
I did.
But sadly,
I lost all that.
If that's so,
it's no big deal.
Man, I hate it
when it's hot.
Why are you covering
your sword with a cloth?
What, uh, what cloth?
Let me see it, Laios.
No, I would rather
you didn't.
Let me see it now!
So what should we
do with him?
My vote is that we
form a circle
and kick his ass.
Go wash this off
immediately.
You find anything?
All that's here
is a strange building,
but there's nowhere
else to go.
What?
You mean this thing?
Oh!
It's probably
an automated trolley.
Let's go inside
and have a look.
I doubt this thing
works anymore.
If we took it apart
and sold the pieces,
I bet it would sell
pretty well.
Why is it moving?
Senshi,
what the heck
did you do?
It wasn't me.
This might be
the kind of trolley
that moves
when people board.
I'm gonna try
reading this
information sign,
so why don't you
all just sit tight
for a bit?
I don't really think
any of this
is gonna help us.
Well,
I'm not sensing
anything dangerous
just yet,
so why don't we
try going as far
as it'll take us?
I guess I'll brew
some tea.
What's that?
These are dryad seeds
I roasted earlier.
You draw the magic circle?
I think so,
but I don't know
if it's working
right or not.
It's a little bit slow,
but it does seem
to be heating.
So I've been meaning
to ask,
why'd you and your sister
become adventurers anyway?
Huh?
Us?
You two don't really
strike me as
get-rich-quick
kind of folks.
It's a bit of a
long story,
but when I was
in my teens,
I got fed up
with the people
in my hometown.
So I went to school,
then joined the military.
Unfortunately,
I didn't fit in
there either.
At some point,
I joined a passing
merchant caravan.
Wait,
he's a deserter?
I did chores for them
as we gradually
traveled south.
Fallon was living
at the magic school
in the area,
so I stopped by
just to see her,
but she insisted
on following me.
The two of us
arrived at this island
together.
When we first got here,
gold stripping
was prospering,
which meant there was
plenty of guard work.
Us taking those jobs
is what led to us
entering this dungeon.
And that's our story.
Hard to believe
you did all that
without a single plan.
Your whole thing
makes sense,
but why did
Fallon tag along?
I feel like her life
would have been easier
at school.
If I'm being honest,
Fallon's childhood
wasn't great for her.
She had a talent
for magic,
but was shunned for it.
I got sick of living
in that environment,
so I left the village
a year before she did.
Until magic school,
no,
until she met Marcil,
she probably ate
her meals alone.
When I think about it,
it hurts my heart.
Though, mentally,
Fallon's a lot tougher
than I could ever
dream of being,
so it's quite possible
she didn't let it
bother her.
Regardless,
I decided I'd never
leave Fallon behind
again.
Not till she meets
someone new that she
wants to be with
all the time anyway.
What are you doing?
Stop it!
Fallon, she...
she would always
pick up weird things
and bring them to me.
Like strange smelling
fruits or bits of grass
and herbs.
I never knew why
she chose me specifically.
I bet she wanted
to eat that stuff
with you.
I...
I want to eat another good meal
with her again.
I'm sure we will soon.
With the way I'm looking at it,
Fallon is most like
bacon and eggs
right now.
You know,
if we're comparing souls
to eggs like before.
There's an egg on some bacon
and they're stuck together.
However,
it still seems possible
to separate them cleanly.
That's how I see Fallon.
In comparison,
Izutsumi is like
a mixed omelet.
If you work hard enough at it,
you can remove
the various ingredients,
but I imagine
that would probably cause
the egg portion of it
to fall apart.
Because of that,
in Izutsumi's particular case,
we'd need to find
a more delicate
and elaborate method
to help her.
Then,
what you're saying is,
if we manage to cut off
her lower half,
then we'll be able
to turn Fallon
into a human again?
It can't possibly
be that simple.
At the time,
I made sure to preserve
some of the dragon meat
in order for us
to eat it later,
but all of it
ended up turning back
into flesh and blood
and fused with Fallon.
However,
there were parts of the meat
that didn't return
to the dragon,
and that was everything
we all ate for dinner
that night.
Meat digested by another creature
loses its identity.
In this dungeon,
where life and death
are completely ambiguous,
that could very well
be the one clear rule
it has.
So basically,
if we ate
the entire dragon,
isn't it perfectly reasonable
to assume that it would
drive its soul
away from Fallon?
What can I say?
I never expected
all that from you.
I thought you would
be opposed to that stuff.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm still against
reviving people.
But as far as we've seen,
if Fallon is still alive,
your main focus right now
is to find her
and free her
from the dungeon,
isn't it?
I'd be more than happy
to help you out with that.
Eating the entire dragon?
Sorry,
but, uh,
how many servings
do you think that is?
Why is that
where your mind goes?
Because we need to know!
This is the best plan
we've come up with
so far.
Do you have any
better ideas?
In order to take claim
to what you kill,
you have to eat it first.
Of course!
Why didn't I think
of that before?
We've been doing
exactly that
this whole time!
Although,
she's huge.
If we each ate
one kilogram a day,
then it'd take over
ten years
to finish the whole thing.
You really think
I could eat
a kilogram's worth?
Considering the state
she's in,
we really don't have
that kind of time.
Looks like we're gonna
have to reach out
to others
for a little help,
then.
It's time to call on
all those personal
connections you've
been building up.
You make it sound
like I have more
than I do.
I know there's
more than zero.
Surely some faces
come to mind.
Hmm.
The orcs seem like
they'd eat a lot,
so that's promising.
The Golden Castle
residents,
they won't have
too much of an appetite,
but they have the numbers
and livestock
to make up for it.
And I think
Namari and Shuro's
parties would likely
join if we appeal
to their emotions.
Oh, and there's
Kogru, too!
He seemed interested
in monster cuisine.
Uh, that's pretty much
all I can think of.
That's plenty.
But still not enough
to eat a dragon.
One more mid-sized
group would do it.
Well, at the very least,
our goal from here
on out to become
crystal clear.
One!
Release the winged lion
from the depths
of this dungeon!
Two!
With the lion's help,
we've finally
neutralized the mad mage!
Three!
Gather people
who are willing
to assist in
eating Falun's
dragon parts!
I suddenly have hope
this is gonna work!
It sounds like
it's gonna be
one hell of a party.
We're not gonna find
a mid-sized group
in the dungeon.
What's this feeling
of uneasiness?
The dungeon air
has become
pretty stagnant.
While you guys
were down there
this last time,
it changed
a decent amount again.
Wait, what do you mean?
You'll understand it
when you see it.
But, to be honest,
I don't think
these are the kind
of changes
the folks behind us
will like.
Don't you dare
consume that!
There's something
going on up there.
Walking mushrooms.
If we took
Falun's dragon parts
and cooked up
some steaks,
would that be
a good garnish
for them?
Or maybe a stew
would be better.
We could make
stock from the...
That's enough!
Now's not really
the time to be
crafting a Falun menu.
I'm so hungry!
Let's start
prepping something.
You got it!
Dungeon food.
To eat
or be eaten.
There is no
hierarchy here.
Only the simple
concept that eating
is a privilege
of the living.
Ah, dungeon food.
Delicious
in dungeon.